<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/collections/all.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/collections/all"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/collections/earth-products.atom"/>
  <title>Natural Wholesalers </title>
  <updated>2021-06-11T08:40:43+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Natural Wholesalers </name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/4329800695886</id>
    <published>2021-06-11T08:40:43+02:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T08:40:43+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/ghee-clarified-butter-earth-products"/>
    <title>Ghee (Clarified Butter) | Earth Products</title>
    <s:type>Health food</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Earth Products</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0079/1606/0730/products/earth_products_ghee.jpg?v=1572431560"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Earth Products<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Health food<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            95.00
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><p><strong>Earth Products</strong>' Ghee (230g) is a healthy alternative to ordinary butter and cooking oils.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ghee is clarified butter, meaning that all water and milk solids have been removed, making it perfect for those who are lactose-intolerant or casein-intolerant </li>
<li>Contains no dairy BUT is not vegan-friendly (as it is an animal byproduct)</li>
<li>Has a delicious buttery, nutty and slightly sweet flavour </li>
<li>Perfect for Asian and Indian dishes, cooking, frying and baking</li>
<li>Loaded with vitamins <span>A, D, E and K</span>
</li>
<li>Has a high smoke point of <span>250°C</span>
</li>
<li>Has a long shelf life</li>
<li>Free of trans-fats, preservatives and additives</li>
<li>Ethically and humanely sourced from grass-fed cows in the Midlands</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ingredients</h2>
<p>Clarified butter</p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>sidebar_brands</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/4329800695886</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="ZAR">95.00</s:price>
      <s:sku>EP006</s:sku>
      <s:grams>0</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1758167892026</id>
    <published>2021-05-10T09:24:29+02:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-10T09:24:29+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/earth-products-non-irradiated-turmeric-powder-250-g"/>
    <title>Earth Products Non-Irradiated Turmeric Powder (250 g)</title>
    <s:type>Superfoods</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Earth Products</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0079/1606/0730/products/TurmericPowderfg.png?v=1628259865"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Earth Products<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Superfoods<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            29.00
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><strong>Turmeric</strong><span> powder is a common culinary spice in Indian cuisine and is also used  in Ayurvedic medicine, fast making its way to the natural health treasure chest! Turmeric has powerful anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties! Most turmeric found in stores has been irradiated which removes the beneficial therapeutic properties, so make sure that you only use </span><strong>non-irradiated turmeric powder!</strong><br>
<h3 style="display: inline !important;"></h3>
<h3 style="display: inline !important;">Health benefits of turmeric</h3>
<ul>
<li>Acts as a digestive aid - helps to stimulate the gall bladder to produce more bile, which is important to break down dietary fat</li>
<li>Studies have shown that Curcumin can reduce the growth of cancerous cells and new blood vessels in tumours</li>
<li>The powerful anti-inflammatory and oxidative properties of curcumin make it a perfect choice to reduce arthritis symptoms</li>
<li>Helps to prevent Alzheimer's and promotes brain and neurotransmitter balance</li>
<li>For bronchial asthma stir a teaspoon of the powder in a glass of milk or preferred drink and drink up to 3 times a day</li>
<li>Can also be used in DIY skin care products to naturally cleanse, purify and brighten the skin! </li>
<li>Non-irradiated turmeric is a key ingredient in Golden Milk (haldi doodh) - an Ayurvedic health drink</li>
</ul>
<h3>How to use Turmeric Powder</h3>
<p>Turmeric powder can be added to food dishes, sauces, soups and drinks like tea and milk! It is best to have on an empty stomach. </p>
<p><strong>Turmeric Tea</strong> - Dissolve 5 grams (about 1 teaspoon) of turmeric powder into boiled water or almond milk. You can also add lemon, honey, ginger and other spices to enhance the flavour of this delicious drink.</p>
<p><strong>Ingredients:</strong></p>
<p>100% Non-irradiated Turmeric Powder</p>
<ul></ul>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em> <em>This product has not been evaluated by the Medicines Control Council. This medicine is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any illness. </em></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>Earth Products Non-Irradiated Turmeric Powder</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Non-irradiated turmeric powder South Africa</s:tag>
    <s:tag>sidebar_brands</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Turmeric Powder</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1758167892026</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="ZAR">29.00</s:price>
      <s:sku>EP001</s:sku>
      <s:grams>500</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1315173302330</id>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:54:06+02:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:54:06+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/earth-ear-candles-pack-of-two-for-ear-health-clarity"/>
    <title>Earth Ear Candles - Pack of Two for Ear Health &amp; Clarity</title>
    <s:type>Ear Candles</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Earth Products</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0079/1606/0730/products/earth_products_ear_candles.jpg?v=1572434839"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Earth Products<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Ear Candles<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            41.00
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><ul>
<li>Helps to unblock the ears, remove ear wax, clear the ear canal &amp; improve hearing</li>
<li>Traditionally used by First People Native American Hopis to help with tinnitus</li>
<li>Also traditionally used to assist with ear congestion and sinusitis</li>
<li>Calming &amp; relaxing</li>
<li>Contains bees wax &amp; essential oils of soothing chamomile &amp; lavender</li>
<li>FREE reducer to fit into the ear</li>
</ul>
<h2>What are Ear Candles?</h2>
<p>EARTH ear candles are cotton tubes, dipped in beeswax, with added essential oils of chamomile and lavender. Ear candles were traditionally used by First People Native American Hopis to relieve ear noises (tinnitus), congestion and sinusitis and to remove wax build up from the ear canal, as well as to relax and improve hearing. </p>
<h3>How to use ear candles</h3>
<p><strong>NB: Do not use ear candles on your own!</strong><span> </span>They are very relaxing, but can pose a fire hazard! Traditional ear candling is easy to do, but should be done by a friend or a practitioner (since you're working with fire, you actually want one of you on the ball and alert!)</p>
<p>You will need:</p>
<ul>
<li>The ear candles</li>
<li>A paper plate</li>
<li>A bowl of water to extinguish the ear candle when it is finished</li>
<li>Matches</li>
</ul>
<p>Cut a cross into the paper plate and push the ear candle through the opening, leaving a few centimeters on the side closest to the ear. Push the reducer onto the ear candle if you like (this helps with smaller ears but is not essential)</p>
<p>The person should lie on his/her side, with the upper part of the head on a pillow (let the ear of the side you're lying on actually be clear of the pillow).  Make sure the person is lying comfortably and cover with a blanket if desired. This procedure is very relaxing when it is done by an experienced person.</p>
<p>Insert the ear candle into the ear, with the paper plate protecting the head and hair from any dripping wax.</p>
<p>Light the candle and watch while it burns down to approx 5 cm, just enough to remove It. This will take a few minutes and the person who is receiving the ear candling should not be left alone.</p>
<p>Once the ear candle has burned down, remove from the ear and douse in the bowl of water. </p>
<p>Repeat on the other side. </p>
<ul></ul>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em> <em>This product has not been evaluated by the Medicines Control Council. This medicine is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any illness. </em></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>bees wax ear candles</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Ear candles</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Ear Candles South Africa</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Organic ear candles</s:tag>
    <s:tag>sidebar_brands</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1315173302330</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="ZAR">41.00</s:price>
      <s:sku>EP002</s:sku>
      <s:grams>60</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1780689502266</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T15:37:29+02:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-21T15:37:29+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/earth-products-organic-red-henna-powder-250g"/>
    <title>Earth Products Organic Red Henna Powder (250g)</title>
    <s:type>Hair &amp; Skin</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Earth Products</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0079/1606/0730/products/Earth_Products_Henna.jpg?v=1533034613"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Earth Products<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Hair &amp; Skin<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            47.50
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><div>
<p><span><strong>Henna</strong> is used to naturally colour hair and can also be made into a paste to perform body art and popular henna tattoos! Store bought 'henna' is often adulterated with chemicals that are bad for your health. Earth Products Pure Henna Powder is 100% organic and contains no added chemicals - only 100% pure henna!</span></p>
<ul>
<li>Improve hair growth and prevent hair from falling out</li>
<li>A scalp tonic for dandruff prone hair </li>
<li>Can reduce hair from breaking and split ends</li>
<li>Avoid the health risks of chemical hair dyes </li>
<li>Will leave hair feeling amazingly soft and naturally conditioned!</li>
</ul>
<h3>How to apply Henna to Hair</h3>
<p><span>Mix approximately 1/2 cup Henna powder (you might need more, depends on your hair length) with strong rooibos or ceylon tea, or coffee or red wine to soften the intense red colour. Apply paste to one strand of hair for 15 minutes and wash and blow-dry to gauge intensity before henna-ing your whole head. </span></p>
<h3>To use Henna Powder as a Body Art Paste (Tattoos!)</h3>
<p><span>1. Sift enough Henna to make about 1 1/4 cups dry, sifted Henna powder</span></p>
<p><span>2. Add 2 teaspoons Instant Coffee to about 1 1/2 cups of water, place in a pot and boil until it reduces to about a 3/4 cup of dark liquid</span></p>
<p><span>3. Mix just enough coffee liquid into the Henna powder to create a thick paste.The hot liquid will make the powder ball up a little, so be sure to mix it into a well-blended and smooth paste</span></p>
<p><span>4. Add about 2 TS of Lemon Juice – fresh is best!</span></p>
<p>5. Add about 5 drops each of<span> </span>Eucalyptus Oil<span> </span>and<span> </span>Clove Oil, and mix in.This should make a thin paste, without being runny. If it is too runny, add a little more sifted Henna powder. If it is too thick, add a little more concentrated coffee liquid, or plain water. Allow the paste to settle and cool for about 2 hours.</p>
<p><span>Have fun!</span></p>
<h3><strong>Ingredients:</strong></h3>
<p><span>100% Organic Henna Powder</span></p>
</div>
<h2><span></span></h2>
<ul></ul>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em> <em>This product has not been evaluated by the Medicines Control Council. This medicine is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any illness. </em></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>Earth Products Pure Organic Henna Powder</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Organic henna powder for hair</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Pure henna powder for hair</s:tag>
    <s:tag>sidebar_brands</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1780689502266</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="ZAR">47.50</s:price>
      <s:sku>EP004</s:sku>
      <s:grams>500</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1315179036730</id>
    <published>2020-12-04T16:07:41+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T16:07:41+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/earth-organic-apple-cider-vinegar-with-the-mother"/>
    <title>Earth Organic Apple Cider Vinegar: With the Mother! (500ml)</title>
    <s:type>Apple Cider Vinegar</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Earth Products</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0079/1606/0730/products/Earth_Apple_Cider_Vinegar.jpg?v=1530540654"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Earth Products<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Apple Cider Vinegar<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            86.50
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><ul>
<li>Contains 'the mother' (collagen strands that are not present in most commercial apple cider vinegar)</li>
<li>Promotes beautiful skin and vibrant health</li>
<li>Removes arterial plaque, bodily toxins and infections</li>
<li>Guards against candida, thrush, moulds, bacteria and germs</li>
<li>Helps to regulate calcium metabolism</li>
<li>Normalises urine pH, relieves bladder infections and the frequent urge to urinate</li>
<li>Helps digestion, prevents and relieves acid reflux and heartburn</li>
<li>Helps with sore throat, laryngitis, ticklish throat, clears throat congestion and gum infections (use as a gargle)</li>
<li>Detoxes the body, reduces bloating &amp; cellulite and helps with weight loss</li>
<li>Applied topically, helps with acne, dandruff, athlete's foot, shingles, sunburn and other burns</li>
<li>Helps banish itching, dandruff, dry hair and baldness (use as a hair wash or body rinse)</li>
<li>Relieves the pain of arthritis and gout by removing crystals and toxins from joints, tissues, organs and the whole body</li>
</ul>
<h2>What is Apple Cider Vinegar (ACV)?</h2>
<p>EARTH Apple Cider Vinegar is made from organically grown apples and contains the famous 'Mother' = th<span>e collagen strands that help keep making vinegar. These appear as little floaty bits in the vinegar and are essential in maintaining the therapeutic benefits of the Apple Cider Vinegar. They are not usually present in non-organic store-bought apple cider vinegar,  </span></p>
<h3>How to use Apple Cider Vinegar</h3>
<p>You can drink Apple Cider Vinegar as is, but most people prefer to dilute it.</p>
<p>This is a good mix:</p>
<p><span>Add one tablespoon Apple Cider Vinegar,  1/2 juiced lemon and one teaspoon honey or maple syrup into a cup of warm water. Drink first thing in the morning, after working out, or when dehydrated.</span></p>
<p><span>You can also add a tablespoon of Apple Cider Vinegar to a 1/2 cup of warm water and sip slowly to relieve indigestion, heartburn or acid reflux. </span></p>
<p><span>Topically, dilute one tablespoon Apple Cider Vinegar and sponge onto itchy skin, athlete's foot or other skin conditions, or use as a hair rinse for scalp problems or dandruff. </span></p>
<ul></ul>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em> <em>This product has not been evaluated by the Medicines Control Council. This medicine is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any illness. </em></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>ACV</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Apple Cider Vinegar for heartburn</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Apple Cider Vinegar to lose weght</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Apple Cider Vinegar with the Mother South Africa</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Earth Organic Apple Cider Vinegar</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Organic ACV</s:tag>
    <s:tag>sidebar_brands</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://naturalwholesalers.com/products/1315179036730</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="ZAR">86.50</s:price>
      <s:sku>EP003</s:sku>
      <s:grams>500</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
</feed>
